SYLVIA ZHANG

Email: sylvia.zhang.it@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sylviazhangca GitHub: https://github.com/S1Y333

6 years of computer science engineering study, 2 years of work experience as a Software Developer, and 1.5 year accumulated hands-on experience in Full Stack Projects. Oracle certified Java Professional Developer. Demonstrate a strong sense of responsibility, open communication skills, problem solving, teamwork and a self-motivated work ethic in various industries.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

MERN Stack E-Commerce Project (React+ Redux + Node.js + Express + MongoDB)

Sep – ongoing 2023

- Built a complex e-commerce web application using React and Redux for the front end and Node.js, Express framework for the backend with advanced searching, filtering, and recommending products.
- Performed advanced MongoDB queries using Mongoose and executed CRUD for products and categories
- Developed star rating system, generated discount coupon code, supported multiple image uploads for user
- Designed role-based access control, credit card payment with Stripe, and order management system for admin

MERN **Stack React Application Website** (React+ Node.js + Express + MongoDB)

Jun - Aug 2023

- Created a place social App for users to register/log in to post places with input validation and token authentication
- Implemented the RESTful APIs with Node.js to handle HTTP requests and connected to the MongoDB database
- Integrated with Google Maps to show places on the map and image file upload to enhance user experience

Full-Stack E-Commerce Website (Angular + Node.js + MySQL +Spring Boot +Stripe)

Aug – Dec 2022

- Built a real-time eCommerce App with Angular, Bootstrap for the front end and Spring Boot for the back end.
- Implemented the RESTful APIs with Node.js to handle HTTP requests and responses and created checkout reactive forms with input validation and secure Stripe credit card payment.
- Set up user authentication, order history database with full CRUD support using MySQL, connected the Stripe API for the payment, and deployed to render.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Media Specialist, Brandtalk Media Inc, Vaughan, ON

Jun 2018 - Oct 2021

- Led the event project for the tourism client to design & build the landing page on woobox.com, which generated more than 2000+entries and increased sales by 40%
- Developed and optimized Facebook Ad to increase Click Through Rate & Link clicks by 30% and provide training for to help team members shorten the transition time by one week
- Managed 4 customers' social media, including TD bank, CILAR non-profit organization, handling daily social media service and last-minute request, receiving 98% client satisfaction

Java Teacher and Coordinator, Wells Academy, Markham, ON

Jun 2018 - Oct 2019

- Taught Grade 11 credit course ICS3U: Introduction to Computer Science using BlueJ IDE
- Designed the practical course plan & tests to help students make small projects like a calculator using Java at the end of the course, and 95% of them achieved this goal.
- Organized school events from start to finish, which increased program registration by 60% and helped more than
 500 students connect with their instructors.

Software Engineer, China Ship Scientific Research Center Jiangsu, China

2009 - 2011

- Built a Human Resources system based on SSH (Spring, Struts2, Hibernate) framework as a team member.
- Implemented the main functions covering get/add/update/delete employees.
- Deployed the MySQL Database to the Server and maintained it up to date for the test stage.

TECH STACK

React, Node.js, Express.js, Agile, JAVA, Spring Boot, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Angular, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, CI/CD, CircleCI

EDUCATION

Certified Professional: Java SE 11 Developer, Oracle	2022
Hootsuite Social Marketing Certificate	2020
Digital Marketing Certificate, York University, Toronto, ON, Canada	2020
Master of Engineering: Computer Software Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, China	2012
Bachelor of Engineering: in Electronic Information Engineering, JXSTNU, Nanchang, China	2009